
<name>
1: LBG Squad
<type>
Squad, in-house
  - small team
  - Share team members and effort across our division of the bank
<action>
What did I do?
 - 
 - 
 -
<impact>
What did my squad do?
 - Build courage to challenge the brief and guide our clients to better challenges
 - Communicate the value of design in a financial services environment 
 - Build our platform
 - Drive group-wide transformation through impact of design on customers

<name>
2: Typeform
<type>
1st designer / future team
  - No team, leveraged leaderless teams
  - Collaborated with other directors to change behaviour and generate outcomes across the product org
  - Coaching CPO on service line approach and journey management
<action>
What did I do?
 - 
 - 
 -
<impact>
What did the teams I helped do?
 - Change of behaviours in other teams
 - Silo busting
 - Co-designing strategy
 - Product org changes towards service-ownership

<name>
3: Designit
<type>
Design studio executive in Big4 tech consult
- Leadership team of for execs reporting into MD
<action>
What did I do?
 - 
 - 
 -
<impact>
What did my teams do?
 - Teams led created pitches and won business (luxury brand pitch)
 - Teams upped their game in solution-shaping
 - Team worked in an incompatible culture and let their mojo influence the parent org

<name>
4: Nile
<type>
Boutique design consultancy
- Team of 15 across design specialisms
- Close partnership with MD to cover for founder on mat leave
<action>
What did I do?
 - 
 - 
 -
<impact>
What did my team do?
 - GSJ Participation
 - Designed and delivered new service offering
 - Leads stepping up for extra engagement in order to keep customer happy through founder maternity leave


<name>
5: Accenture (Avanade)
<type>
Big 4 tech consulting firm. Immature design business when I joined
Built UK arm of global design organisation
<action>
What did I do?
 - Advocate for design. Over, and over, and over, until I was blue in the face
 - Collaborate with my Global and European team-mates (we were building a new capability so made the most of our mix of backgrounds and skills)
 - Create a dome of protection where my people could thrive and product great work. Accenture is a hyper-accountability environment. There was quite a lot of negotiating required to bring design thinking successfully into the company culture.
 - Organised the coming together of the digital strategy (Sitecore business unit) and XD teams into a larger, cross-functional department
<impact>
What impact did my team have?
 - Bring about change of attitude in internal marketplace. The lead to customers coming to us instead of going out to agencies and our billings revenue to increase
 - Evidenced quality and delivery, which in turn allowed UK leadership to win further budget for growth
 - Built on their strengths as thought leaders in enterprise technology to claim thought leadership in workplace transformation
 - Competed successfully 
 - Helped me bring in my chargeability targets and the right employee survey results (it was adventure and I think most of the team was happy to be there)

<name>
6: Currys
<type>
in-house
<action>
What did I do?
 - Give a broken team a huge hug and tell them they have my 100% permission to question assumptions and kick ass
 - Advocate for UCD as part of a large technology transformation, keeping the group honest, and human-focused
 - Establish ways of working between remote dev unit in Paris and design teams in London
<impact>
What impact did my team have?
 - Successfully re-platform the three largest e-commerce websites in the UK in time for Peak trading
 - Collaborate with external consultants while nurturing their in-house culture and setting up stronger, more resilient teams
 - Deliver a foundational base for the parent company's turnaround (my team didn't turn the Currys business around on their own but they sure as hell made our customers more likely to make up with us).
 - Support and adapt the processes and behaviours to land a marketing automation and experience management toolset

<name>
7: Vodafone R&D
<type>
in-house
<action>
What did I do?
 - 
 - 
 -
<impact>
What impact did my team have?
 - Bring about change of attitude in internal marketplace. Curstomers coming to us instead of going out to agencies
 - Evidenced quality and delivery, which in turn allowed UK leadership to win further budget for growth
 - Built on their strengths as thought leaders in enterprise technology to claim thought leadership in workplace transformation
 - Competed successfully 





